<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Nextcloud on ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/tags/nextcloud/</link><description>Recent content in Nextcloud on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.125.1</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 19:54:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/tags/nextcloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setup the Nextcloud Snap Package with HTTPS and a separate data path</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/setup-the-nextcloud-snap-package-with-https-and-a-separate-data-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 19:54:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/setup-the-nextcloud-snap-package-with-https-and-a-separate-data-path/</guid><description>https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud I have been using the Nextcloud snap package for a long time, but some recent system changes in my colocation facility mean that it is time for a big upgrade. Rather than migrate my existing Nextcloud instance, I have decided to build a new install and here are my goals for the new installation:
Use lets encrypt to have automatic and valid HTTPS certificates Have the data path for Nextcloud on a HDD and the rest of the host OS on an SSD.</description></item><item><title>Backup Nextcloud with RCLONE</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 21:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</guid><description>I’ve made previous posts about backing cloud services with RCLONE – Backup Google Photos with Rclone – and this post will detail how to backup a self-hosted cloud service, Nextcloud.
Get started with Nextcloud There are a lot of benefits to running your own private ‘cloud’ storage system, but for me, my top concern is privacy and Nextcloud gives me the ability to take accountability for my own data. With this in mind, I am conscious of my Nextcloud server going offline or suffering data loss, so I want a way to create 1 or more backups of my datacentre hosted, Nextcloud data on my home NAS.</description></item></channel></rss>