<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/</link><description>Recent content on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.134.0</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Complete 2024 Guide: How to expand a Ubuntu LVM LV to use all space on the PV</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-expand-an-lvm-lv-to-use-all-space-on-the-pv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-expand-an-lvm-lv-to-use-all-space-on-the-pv/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>2024 Update&lt;/strong> - I found myself stuck in this situation again, my Ubuntu root partition was completely full to the brim&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m scrambling to remove apt chache and pruning and and all docker images, but then I run &lt;code>vgdisplay&lt;/code> only to reaslise that my LVM LV isn&amp;rsquo;t even using the full amount of physical disk space (this is a VM and I have just expanded the VMDK file). Thankfully I wrote this blog post 4 years ago as a how-to. Well now I am going to give this post a refresh and this includes some extra details which I needed during the panic of a full disk.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing Llama3.1 (8B) With LM Studio</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/testing-llama3_1-with-gpt4all/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/testing-llama3_1-with-gpt4all/</guid><description>Taking a look at the the latest open source llama 3.1 model after its July 2024 release. Testing its performance and accuracy with GPT4ALL.</description></item><item><title>Feeding My Cat With Home Assistant</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/feeding-my-cat-with-home-assistant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/feeding-my-cat-with-home-assistant/</guid><description>Tired of manually feeding your cat? Learn how to automate your Tuya cat feeder with Home Assistant and ensure your furry friend is always fed on time.</description></item><item><title>Using an Amazon FireHD8 as a Home Assistant Dashboard Control Panel</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/home-assistant-firehd8-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 04:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/home-assistant-firehd8-dashboard/</guid><description>Home Assistant has continues to make progress in the self-hosted home automation field, so let&amp;#39;s take a look at using the Amazon FireHD8 tablet as a control panel</description></item><item><title>Testing Llama3 With LM Studio</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/testing-llama3-with-lmstudio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/testing-llama3-with-lmstudio/</guid><description>Taking a look at the the latest open source llama 3 model after its April 2024 release. Testing its performance and accuracy with LM Studio.</description></item><item><title>Generating Artwork With Stable Diffusion - April 2024 Edition</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/generating-artwork-with-stable-diffusion-april-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/generating-artwork-with-stable-diffusion-april-2024/</guid><description>A look at the state of artwork generation with stable-diffusion in April 2024. Investigating if (local) stable-diffusion can reliably produce enjoyable artwork.</description></item><item><title>Home Assistant HTTPS Certificates with Tailscale, Traefik and CoreDNS</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/homeassistant-tls-with-tailscale-traefik/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/homeassistant-tls-with-tailscale-traefik/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve explained how to use Tailscale&amp;rsquo;s MagicDNS and HTTPS certificate feature to generate a TLS cert for your Home Assistant install: &lt;a href="../homeassistant-tls-with-tailscale">Homeassistant Enable MagicDNS and HTTPS Certificates in Tailscale&lt;/a>. That setup required you to reformat the TLS cert and copy it to the Home Assistant container&amp;hellip; it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be to much of a task to automate those actions, but fortunately there is now a superior method of applying and renewing a Tailscale cert for HASS (and many other self-hosted services). Let us dig in to that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python Development in Docker Containers</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-development-in-docker-containers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-development-in-docker-containers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker Compose is a powerful tool that allows developers to define and manage multi-container applications. In this blog post, we will explore a &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker Compose&lt;/a> file for developing &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/">Python&lt;/a> applications. Specifically, we will analyze the following Docker Compose file:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">version&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;3&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">services&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">mypthontool&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">image&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">python:3.9&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">volumes&lt;/span>:
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> - &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">./:/app/&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">tty&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">true&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pr</description></item><item><title>Automating Postgres Deployment with Docker Compose and Init Scripts</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automating-postgres-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automating-postgres-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-running-postgresql-in-a-docker-container-using-docker-compose">Introduction to Running PostgreSQL in a Docker Container using Docker Compose&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this blog post, we will explore how to run &lt;a href="https://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL&lt;/a> in a Docker container using &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/compose/">Docker Compose&lt;/a>. We will also break down and explain the &lt;code>init-user-db.sh&lt;/code> script that is executed at startup to initialize the PostgreSQL tables. Running PostgreSQL in a Docker container provides several benefits, including ease of deployment, portability, and isolation. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and understand the process!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up Wyoming Piper with Docker Compose</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/wyoming-piper-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/wyoming-piper-docker-compose/</guid><description>&lt;p>In previous posts I have been using Docker Compose to deploy the constituent components of a fully local Home Assistant voice assistant. In this blog post, we will guide you through setting up Wyoming Piper using Docker Compose. Piper is a fast, local neural text to speech system originally optimised for the Raspberry Pi 4. It supports many languages, and voice samples: &lt;a href="https://rhasspy.github.io/piper-samples">https://rhasspy.github.io/piper-samples&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wyoming Piper is a speech recognition and natural language understanding system that can be used for voice control in various applications. It uses the Rhasspy framework and provides support for different languages and voices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Use a Docker Compose File for Wyoming Whisper</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/wyoming-whisper-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/wyoming-whisper-docker-compose/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post, we will go over how to use a Docker Compose file to deploy and configure Wyoming Whisper. Wyoming Whisper is an open-source, lightweight voice assistant designed to run on a Raspberry Pi or other low-powered device. The impetus for this compose defined container is to intergate with a Home Assistant 2023.5 container and ultimate have a fully local voice assistant. Whisper will provide our speech-to-text service and the Wyoming protocol is how it will be integrated with Home Assistant.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Homeassistant Enable MagicDNS and HTTPS Certificates in Tailscale</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/homeassistant-tls-with-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/homeassistant-tls-with-tailscale/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tailscale is a virtual private network (VPN) service that allows secure remote access to resources across different networks. It offers a feature called MagicDNS that enables you to access your resources using a domain name instead of an IP address. Additionally, you can use HTTPS certificates to encrypt traffic between clients and servers, ensuring secure communication. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explain how to enable MagicDNS and HTTPS certificates in Tailscale and how to add a TLS certificate to Home Assistant using Tailscale.
The most practical benifit for using Home Assistant within a Tailscale network is that it removes the requirement for network port forwarding and exposing services publicly, whilst still allowing your devices to access it from outside your local network. This blog post aims to give you the starting stes required to setup MagicDNS and HTTPS certificates in Tailscale, create a certificate on your home server and install that certificate in a Home Assistant docker container.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Passing Through an NVMe Drive to an ESXi Virtual Machine</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/esxi-nvme-disk-passthrough/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 18:50:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/esxi-nvme-disk-passthrough/</guid><description>&lt;p>ESXi is a powerful hypervisor that allows for the virtualization of multiple operating systems on a single physical machine. However, there are times when you may need to pass through a physical device, such as an NVMe drive, to a virtual machine. In this blog post, we will explore the steps required to pass through an NVMe drive to an ESXi virtual machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before proceeding, ensure that you have the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Uptime Kuma With Docker Compose</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/running-uptime-kuma-with-docker-compose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 22:06:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/running-uptime-kuma-with-docker-compose/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Uptime-Kuma is an open-source, self-hosted website monitoring tool. It can check the uptime and response time of websites, APIs, and other services at regular intervals and alert you if any of them go down. Uptime-Kuma can be installed on your own server and customized to suit your needs. In this article, we will explore how to set up and run Uptime-Kuma using Docker Compose.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-docker-compose-file">The Docker Compose File&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The following is the Docker Compose file for the Uptime-Kuma service:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome [Back]</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 11:11:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-new-beinging-for-this-blog">A new beinging for this blog&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The ExitCode0 blog is currently migrating. Welcome to the site, please hang tight for more content, coming soon.
This site should now be in hosted on GitHub pages!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to force the Windows 11 upgrade</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-11-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 08:54:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-11-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Windows 11 became available on the 5th October 2021 and for those people with compatible machines, this guide will help you jump the queue and force the Windows 11 upgrade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Before you start…&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Take a backup all all important data onto an external storage device/location.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>set aside at least 1 hour for the upgrade – maybe longer, depending on your internet connection speed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make sure that your Windows 10 installation is up to date with no pending updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="compatibility">Compatibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You might have seen a number of articles and news stories floating around about Windows 11 dropping support for a large number of computers, particularly older systems. The quickest way to test your system’s compatibility with Windows 11 is using the Microsoft &lt;strong>WindowsPCHealthCheckSetup&lt;/strong> tool: &lt;a href="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp" title="https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp">https://aka.ms/GetPCHealthCheckApp&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn off TPLink Smart plug LED</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/turn-off-tplink-smart-plug-led/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 12:43:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/turn-off-tplink-smart-plug-led/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image.png?resize=202%2C161&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Turn off TPLink Smart plug LED - https://github.com/Tombo1001/Kasa-Dark-Mode" />
The HS100/HS110 LED can be bright and obnoxious.
If you are looking to turn off the LED status lights on the TPLink Kasa smart plugs, then look no further – the solution resides in this post. It does involve some Python interaction, but I promise that it is a gentle passing with the programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This solution works for:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Customising the PowerShell prompt to show date and time</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/customising-the-powershell-prompt-to-show-date-and-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 19:55:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/customising-the-powershell-prompt-to-show-date-and-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>Depending on your reason for using the PowerShell prompt at it, it might be useful to include data such as timestamps in your recorded output, to enable better auditing. This post will walk you through the simple steps needed for customising the PowerShell prompt, including how to show the current date and time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What exactly do I mean by the PowerShell prompt and what does the typical prompt look like by default? Well let me dial it back to default and show you:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Bluetooth to a VW RCD 300</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/adding-bluetooth-to-a-vw-rcd-300/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/adding-bluetooth-to-a-vw-rcd-300/</guid><description>&lt;p>I own a basic VW Caddy MK3 (2009) which was equipped with a RCD 300 head unit. It did not come with the aux function/connectivity and this post explains how I added Bluetooth connectivity. This was a very simple installation with no requirement for VCDS coding; the Bluetooth adapter replicates a CD changer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0773P8HM5" title="https://amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0773P8HM5">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71ADP1kOkSL._AC_SL1500_.jpg?w=774&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="RCD 300 bluetooth adapter." />
&lt;/a>
At the time of writing this article, I was able to purchase this adapter on Amazon UK for ~£35 – &lt;a href="https://amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0773P8HM5" title="https://amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0773P8HM5">https://amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B0773P8HM5&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More RTX 3060 Nicehash overclocking</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/more-rtx-3060-nicehash-overclocking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 07:10:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/more-rtx-3060-nicehash-overclocking/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/rtx-nicehash.png?resize=232%2C232&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="RTX 3060 Nicehash overclocking - 25% improvement" />
This is part 2 from my previous post on RTX 3060 Nicehash overclocking settings. I don’t want to edit the previous article because the content still stands to be accurate for the hash rate I achieved. However, I have since learned even more about the card and managed to improve my Nicehash quick miner hash rate by a further 10%!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RTX 3060 Nicehash mining overclock settings</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/rtx-3060-nicehash-mining-overclock-settings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 10:24:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/rtx-3060-nicehash-mining-overclock-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently managed to buy a Gigabyte RTX 3060 without lining the pockets of a scaler, lucky me! I recently discussed how I was able to circumvent the Nvidia crypto mining limitations: &lt;a href="__GHOST_URL__/unlock-rtx-3060-mining-hash-rate/">Unlock RTX 3060 mining hash rate&lt;/a> (that post also includes access to the driver). This doubled the RTX 3060 Nicehash mining rate using the ‘unlocked’ Nvidia beta driver – going from ~22MH/s up to ~40MH/s. Impressive!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I am going to share my RTX 3060 overclock settings, which enabled me to achieve a further 10% uplift in Nicehash performance. But first I must disclaimer that you are responsible for your own hardware and any changes you make are at your own risk. What’s more, modern silicone is a lottery, you might not get these exact mining hash rates, or you might get more; keep an eye on your thermals and protect your card and safety of your system accordingly!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unlock RTX 3060 mining hash rate</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/unlock-rtx-3060-mining-hash-rate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 11:26:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/unlock-rtx-3060-mining-hash-rate/</guid><description>&lt;p>There has been lots of news coverage around the recent mistake made by Nvidia with their RTX 3060 driver allowing uninhibited mining hash rates: a great round-up from &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333544/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-rate-limit-unlock-driver" title="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/16/22333544/nvidia-rtx-3060-ethereum-mining-rate-limit-unlock-driver">The Verge&lt;/a>. A developer driver inadvertently included code used for internal development which removes the hash rate limiter on RTX 3060 in some configurations. The driver has been removed, but there are lots of copies in circulation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are still some limitations, you must have a monitor attached and can only run a single RTX 3060 at a time. However, it is only a matter of time before motivated miners get over the remaining hurdles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Honeygain docker-compose setup</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/honeygain-docker-compose-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:20:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/honeygain-docker-compose-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://r.honeygain.me/TOM30548" title="https://r.honeygain.me/TOM30548">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/honeygain-compose.png?resize=272%2C272&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="honeygain docker-compose -yaml example" />
&lt;/a>
So &lt;a href="https://r.honeygain.me/TOM30548" title="https://r.honeygain.me/TOM30548">Honeygain&lt;/a> has finally arrived as a Docker container and this article will give you everything you need to build your own docker-compose YAML file for faster deployments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the docs provided by the Honeygain devs on the matter here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://honeygain.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018979919-How-to-run-Honeygain-on-Docker-Linux-" title="https://honeygain.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018979919-How-to-run-Honeygain-on-Docker-Linux-">https://honeygain.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018979919-How-to-run-Honeygain-on-Docker-Linux-&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, they do not provide a nice way to deploy time and again from a docker-compose file, scroll down for a template! At the time of writing, you are permitted to run the service on two devices per public IP. Unfortunately, the docker image doesn’t currently support the content delivery feature&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unraid USB Controller Passthrough - VM hot swap USB</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/unraid-usb-controller-passthrough-vm-hot-swap-usb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 16:33:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/unraid-usb-controller-passthrough-vm-hot-swap-usb/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/81koU3VBFOL._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=228%2C342&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Unraid USB Controller Passthrough - Fresco FL1100" />
For the longest time, I have been running VMs on my Unraid server and had the need to passthrough USB devices. I will be the first to admit that I have too many computers and a shrink might classify it as an addition. Coupled with my quest for a clutter-free desk, I have been faced with the issue of swapping USB devices like a keyboard and mouse, from one machine to another Unraid virtual machine (vm).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collect bitcoin price data with python and Coinbase</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/collect-bitcoin-price-data-with-python-and-coinbase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 18:53:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/collect-bitcoin-price-data-with-python-and-coinbase/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cryptocurrencies have been back on the popular agenda lately, thanks mostly to the surging value of Bitcoin. I have been interested, but not massively invested in cryptocurrency for many years. If I had the courage to buy and hold all those years ago, I might be writing to you from a beach – I assure you, this is not the case! I have been &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/writing-to-an-influxdb-server-with-python3/" title="https://exitcode0.net/writing-to-an-influxdb-server-with-python3/">getting into InfluxDB lately&lt;/a> and its fantastic ability to store heaps of time series data. Well, using python and Coinbase, I am going to show you how to collect bitcoin (and other crypto assets) price data and store it in InfluxDB… then we are going to make some neat panels in Grafana to help us realise our data. This is going to be a longer write up than most, so here is here are links to each section:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing to an InfluxDB server with Python3</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/writing-to-an-influxdb-server-with-python3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/writing-to-an-influxdb-server-with-python3/</guid><description>&lt;p>A quick GitHub gist for anyone looking to write to an InfluxDB server with Python3. This is a generic function that accepts three inputs; as an example, I am using temperature data in degrees Celsius.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/image-8-1024x173.png?resize=774%2C131&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Writing to an InfluxDB server with Python3 - DHT11 readings in grafana" />
Turning DHT11 readings into beautiful graphs in Grafana
Once you have your data in influxDB, a great way to visualise it is using &lt;a href="https://grafana.com/" title="https://grafana.com/">Grafana&lt;/a>. I hope to bring you more posts in the future about visualising your python data with Grafana.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fortigate: AP-Bridge with a hardware switch</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-ap-bridge-with-a-hardware-switch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 16:41:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-ap-bridge-with-a-hardware-switch/</guid><description>&lt;p>Following on from a previous post on &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-add-a-vlan-to-a-hardware-switch/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-add-a-vlan-to-a-hardware-switch/">how to setup a VLAN on a Fortigate hardware switch&lt;/a>, this post is going to explain how we can link an AP-bridge SSID to a hardware switch and VLAN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, the only reference material you will need to complete this configuration can be found here: &lt;a href="https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortiap/6.4.0/fortiwifi-and-fortiap-cookbook/252439/configuring-the-fortigate-interface-to-manage-fortiap-units" title="https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortiap/6.4.0/fortiwifi-and-fortiap-cookbook/252439/configuring-the-fortigate-interface-to-manage-fortiap-units">https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortiap/6.4.0/fortiwifi-and-fortiap-cookbook/252439/configuring-the-fortigate-interface-to-manage-fortiap-units&lt;/a>. However, if you have been working with Fortigates and by extension FortiOS for quite some time, you may be wonder where the CAPWAP option vanished to? Fortinet adopted this into the security fabric naming convention. CAPWAP has even been replaced in the CLI by ‘fabric’.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fortigate: Add a VLAN to a hardware switch</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-add-a-vlan-to-a-hardware-switch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 21:30:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fortigate-add-a-vlan-to-a-hardware-switch/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fortigate_VLANs-1024x1024.png?resize=227%2C227&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Fortigate: Add a VLAN to a hardware switch - Configuration Example" />
In this post, we are going to discuss how to add a VLAN to a hardware (sometimes referred to as physical) switch or interface on a Fortigate. It is worth noting that I actually do my testing on a FortiWifi, so I can assure you that this also applies there too. I will be focusing on the configuration which is relevant to FortiOS v6.0 and above, so your millage vary between versions. However, you need can usually be found over at the Fortinet Handbook: &lt;a href="https://docs.fortinet.com/product/fortigate/6.0" title="https://docs.fortinet.com/product/fortigate/6.0">https://docs.fortinet.com/product/fortigate/6.0&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debian 10 - How to upgrade python 3.7 to python 3.9</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-10-how-to-upgrade-python-3-7-to-python-3-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-10-how-to-upgrade-python-3-7-to-python-3-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/debian10-pytohn3.png?resize=217%2C206&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="" />
I have covered this a number of times in the past and the posts have proved popular and useful to many. So, here is my guide for updating to the latest version of Python 3 (3.9) on Debian 10 Buster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To clarify the purpose of this guide, Debian 10 ships with Python 2 (2.7) and Python 3 (3.7) installed at my time of writing. For those wishing to upgrade from python 3.7.X to 3.8.X or 3.9.X, this is the guide for you. If you are trying to configure python 3.7 as your default interpreter when you call ‘&lt;code>python&lt;/code>‘, try this: &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/changing-the-default-python-version-in-debian/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/changing-the-default-python-version-in-debian/">CHANGING THE DEFAULT PYTHON VERSION IN DEBIAN&lt;/a>. This method involves using the ‘&lt;code>update-alternatives&lt;/code>‘ command. We will be using a similar method in this guide, however this time we only do so to give 3.9.X a higher priority to 3.7.X, rather than uninstalling older versions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calculating compound interest with Python 3</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/calculating-compound-interest-with-python-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 21:54:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/calculating-compound-interest-with-python-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/python-compound.png?resize=229%2C213&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Calculating compound interest with Python - exitcode 0" />
Compound stonks only go up!
I have a growing interest in finance and analytics, so it felt like a great idea to start creating my own set of financial tools with Python. This article will explain how I created a simple but effective script for calculating compound interest with Python. I wrote this in Python 3 (as all new Python projects should be from now onwards), but the library dependencies are very lightweight, making this something that could easily be re-written from Python 2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to force the Windows 10 20H2 update</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-10-20h2-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 14:39:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-10-20h2-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you still waiting for your Windows 10 computer to receive the 20H2 update? &lt;strong>Here is how to force the windows 10 20H2 update.&lt;/strong> For many, the update may already available the Windows 10 update settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Win10-Upgrade-1024x441.png?resize=774%2C333&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="How to force the Windows 10 20H2 update - update settings" />
The 20H2 update when available in the Windows 10 update settings.
Microsoft is staggering the over-the-air update as they usually do with new major releases. However if you are tired of hitting ‘check for updates’ in the windows 10 update settings, there is a way to press the issue:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to invoke UAC in a Windows Batch script</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-invoke-uac-in-a-windows-batch-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 11:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-invoke-uac-in-a-windows-batch-script/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is my quick and easy way to raise the privilage level of a Windows Batch script; allowing you to run your code at an administrator level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not a new question and has been asked many times on StackOverflow &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1894967/how-to-request-administrator-access-inside-a-batch-file/10052222#10052222" title="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1894967/how-to-request-administrator-access-inside-a-batch-file/10052222#10052222">forums&lt;/a>. The best answer I was able to find was the following from &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/1012053/dbenham" title="https://stackoverflow.com/users/1012053/dbenham">dbenham&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1894967/how-to-request-administrator-access-inside-a-batch-file/10052222#10052222" title="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1894967/how-to-request-administrator-access-inside-a-batch-file/10052222#10052222">https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1894967/how-to-request-administrator-access-inside-a-batch-file/10052222#10052222&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said there are many ways to skin this cat, so I came up with my own method, all be it derivative. The main difference in the following code is that &lt;strong>you will always get a UAC prompt&lt;/strong> in my variant of the code, even if you are currently running it as an account that is a member of the local administrators group:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To call a bash command with variables in Python</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-call-a-bash-command-with-variables-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-call-a-bash-command-with-variables-in-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>A quick Google of the above only seemed to give me answers for the inverse, calling a python script from a bash shell and handing it variables. At least, the first 3 results showed this and I’m probably not alone when it comes to scrolling down past the StackOverflow articles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I am had to go it alone and the way that I figured out how to call a bash command with variables in Python (3), is a total hack… But it works. This is commonly referred to as ‘getting the job done’ code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitor your public IP address with Python</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/monitor-your-public-ip-address-with-python/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 17:48:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/monitor-your-public-ip-address-with-python/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my lean and effective way to monitor your public IP address with Python, specifically Python3. The script – code and GitHub link below – runs on a continuous loop, which I covered in a previous post: &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-python-infinite-loops-with-while-true/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-python-infinite-loops-with-while-true/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE:&lt;/strong> this code is reliant on the &lt;code>dig&lt;/code> system command – so this essentially only work on a unix based system. I was running this on a Debian install.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to pass through a drive to a UNRAID VM</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-pass-through-a-drive-to-a-unraid-vm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-pass-through-a-drive-to-a-unraid-vm/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently migrated my ‘physical’ Windows 10 desktop to a ‘virtual’ machine running under UNRAID (libvert). This is a quick guide on how I was able to use my existing installation on a SSD and pass it through to a VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-passthrough-a-drive-to-a-vm">Why passthrough a drive to a VM?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In some cases, it might be beneficial to start from scratch when creating a Windows 10 VM on UNRAID, creating a new virtual disk and having a fresh install. I chose to take an alternative path because I was contempt with my Windows install as it was. I had my Steam/Epic Games library downloaded onto one of the two disks already in the system and a number of applications installed and configured just the way I like them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[FIXED] Bose Bluetooth headphones with Windows 10</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fixed-bose-bluetooth-headphones-with-windows-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 22:58:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/fixed-bose-bluetooth-headphones-with-windows-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71jDdUuRi8L._AC_SL1500_.jpg?resize=111%2C154&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="SoundLink® around-ear wireless headphones II - winows 10 drivers" />
I recently moved to a new Windows 10 laptop and experience a number of problems with my &lt;a href="https://www.bose.co.uk/en_gb/products/headphones/over_ear_headphones/soundlink-around-ear-wireless-headphones-ii.html#v=soundlink_ae_headphones_ii_black" title="https://www.bose.co.uk/en_gb/products/headphones/over_ear_headphones/soundlink-around-ear-wireless-headphones-ii.html#v=soundlink_ae_headphones_ii_black">Bose SoundLink II&lt;/a>, Bluetooth headphones. Fortunately, after some playing around with drivers I was able to solve my problem and this post explains how…&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-problem">The Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Poor sound quality&lt;/strong> – with the default drivers, the sound quality was poor and there was a considerable amount of audible noise being delivered to the headphones via the Bluetooth interface. The audio was very lo-fi and the frequency range was dramatically reduced. This resulted in a very thin, tinny sound.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to force the Windows 10 2004 update</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-10-2004-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 21:17:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-force-the-windows-10-2004-update/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you still waiting for your Windows 10 computer to receive the 2004 update? Eager to play with WSL2 like I was? &lt;strong>Here is how to force the windows 10 2004 update.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Microsoft is staggering the over-the-air update as they usually do with new major releases. However if you are tired of hitting ‘check for updates’ in the windows 10 update settings, there is a way to press the issue:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to check if RAM is running in ECC mode</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-check-if-ram-is-running-in-ecc-mode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-check-if-ram-is-running-in-ecc-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>Error Correcting Code (ECC) RAM is a variation of coputer memory which helps to ilimintate data curruption or ‘bit rot’, but it is not always imediately apparent if your system memory is running in ECC mode; here is a quick guide on how to check if your system memory is running in ECC mode. This guide covers Windows and Linux systems, but please ensure that if you are running either system in a virtual machine configuration that this command is ran on the &lt;strong>host&lt;/strong> machine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding WMIC command to the Windows path</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/adding-wmic-command-to-the-windows-path/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 14:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/adding-wmic-command-to-the-windows-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>wmic is not recognized as an internal or external command&lt;/strong> – I was quite shocked to find that a command I use on a very regular basis was not working on a fresh installation of Windows 10 1909 on my trust old ThinkPad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t want to spend hours trying to find out why this was not correct in my system path, but instead, I fixed it and spent the time sharing how to fix the problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To: Raspberry Pi boot from USB</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-raspberry-pi-boot-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 10:31:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-raspberry-pi-boot-from-usb/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Pi enthusiasts have been waiting for official USB boot support on the Raspberry Pi for what feels like a lifetime, but finally it is on the horizon. In this post I will explain how to make your Raspberry Pi boot from USB.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/pi4.jpg?resize=298%2C242&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Raspberry Pi boot from USB - exicode0" />
&lt;strong>WARNING&lt;/strong>: Although this is official, it is still in beta testing, so rock-solid stability is far from certain. Learn more about this beta release &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?t=274595&amp;amp;p=1663644#p1663644" title="https://www.raspberrypi.org/forums/viewtopic.php?t=274595&amp;amp;p=1663644#p1663644">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Copy Paste in vSphere before installing VMware tools</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-in-vsphere-before-installing-vmware-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-in-vsphere-before-installing-vmware-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/clipboard.png?resize=168%2C246&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Copy Paste in vSphere" />
I’ve spent enough time building VMs in vSphere to know that the first few minutes between starting the VM and getting VMware Tools installed is agonising. Similar to my ‘&lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-with-powershell-sendkeys/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-with-powershell-sendkeys/">Copy Paste With Powershell Sendkeys&lt;/a>‘ script, I have another tool written in AutoIT which sends defined keyboard strokes to the system. So this is not &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> ‘copy paste in vSphere’, but it achieves the same goal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatically pause Spotify with the 3CX client</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automatically-pause-spotify-with-the-3cx-client/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 21:35:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automatically-pause-spotify-with-the-3cx-client/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a really old script that I just found in my archive, but it still works all the same. The goal was to write a small script that would automatically pause Spotify with the &lt;a href="https://www.3cx.com/voip/softphone/" title="https://www.3cx.com/voip/softphone/">3CX client&lt;/a> when there was an inbound call.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The script is written in AutoIT, meaning that it is a Windows-only solution. The Windows 3CX CTI client allows you to run a particular executable when an inbound call is received, i.e. when the phone rings. I wanted to pause the manic euro beats so that I could answer my phone and here the caller and uphold professionalism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python 3 SSH with Paramiko</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-3-ssh-with-paramiko/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 18:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-3-ssh-with-paramiko/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a number of projects which I am currently working on which usually involve a raspberry pi and so other TCP enabled object. One project, in particular, is to control a KVM server with buttons connected to a raspberry pi (follow on social media or RSS for that future post). I have been using Python 3 SSH with Paramiko to send commands KVM server from the pi. Here is how I do that…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To: Python infinite loops with while true</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-python-infinite-loops-with-while-true/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-python-infinite-loops-with-while-true/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here is a quick guide on how to create an infinite loop in python using a ‘while true’ statement. There are number of reason that you might want to implement this; a great use case would be outputting a fluctuating variable to the terminal such as a temperature reading from a sensor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/infinite-loops.png?resize=178%2C167&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Python infinite loop - exitcode0" />
loops that make your brain hurt
A ‘while true’ statement allows us to run a sequence of code until a particular condition is met. In order to make that sequence of code run in an infinite loop, we can set the condition to be one that is impossible to reach. Better still, we can simply omit the condition altogether to ensure that the while true loop never ends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to upgrade Ubuntu from 18.04 to 20.04</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-upgrade-ubuntu-from-18-04-to-20-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 19:54:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-upgrade-ubuntu-from-18-04-to-20-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://releases.ubuntu.com/20.04/" title="https://releases.ubuntu.com/20.04/">Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/a> LTS full release is almost upon, with a scheduled release date of &lt;a href="https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2019/10/ubuntu-20-04-release-features" title="https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2019/10/ubuntu-20-04-release-features">April 23rd 2020&lt;/a> (2 days as of writing this). It is packed with lots of great new features and upgrades and the Linux community is very excited to get a hold of it. If you are looking to upgrade ubuntu, there is a quick guide down below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If like me you are already running Ubuntu 18.04 LTS then you might be interested to learn how to upgrade your current version of the distro to 20.04 LTS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup the Nextcloud Snap Package with HTTPS and a separate data path</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/setup-the-nextcloud-snap-package-with-https-and-a-separate-data-path/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 19:54:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/setup-the-nextcloud-snap-package-with-https-and-a-separate-data-path/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud" title="https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Nextcloud_Logo.svg_.png?resize=186%2C131" alt="Nextcloud Snap Package setup" />
&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud" title="https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud">https://snapcraft.io/nextcloud&lt;/a>
I have been using the Nextcloud snap package for a long time, but some recent system changes in my colocation facility mean that it is time for a big upgrade. Rather than migrate my existing Nextcloud instance, I have decided to build a new install and here are my goals for the new installation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Use lets encrypt to have automatic and valid HTTPS certificates&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Have the data path for Nextcloud on a HDD and the rest of the host OS on an SSD&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="host-os-details">Host OS Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For this setup, I am using Ubuntu 18.04 installed on a 30GB SSD backed partition. I then have a 1TB disk attached and mounted to /media.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prevent Screensavers and Lock-screens with Powershell</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/prevent-screensavers-and-lock-screens-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 10:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/prevent-screensavers-and-lock-screens-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>There might be a number of reasons to want to prevent your windows screensavers and lock-screens from engaging and in some cases (no doubt yours if you have hit this article from a search engine) local policy on the machine preventing you from changing these settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Powershell lets us work around this problem and prevent the machine from locking or activating a screensaver.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prevent-screensavers-and-lock-screens">Prevent Screensavers and Lock-screens&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The bulk of the code below has been lifted from this great write up: &lt;a href="https://dmitrysotnikov.wordpress.com/2009/06/29/prevent-desktop-lock-or-screensaver-with-powershell/" title="https://dmitrysotnikov.wordpress.com/2009/06/29/prevent-desktop-lock-or-screensaver-with-powershell/">https://dmitrysotnikov.wordpress.com/2009/06/29/prevent-desktop-lock-or-screensaver-with-powershell/&lt;/a> I just took things one step further by adding an infinite loop. My version of this code will run indefinitely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backup Nextcloud with RCLONE</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 21:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve made previous posts about backing cloud services with RCLONE – &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/">Backup Google Photos with Rclone&lt;/a> – and this post will detail how to backup a self-hosted cloud service, Nextcloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/install/#" title="https://nextcloud.com/install/#">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Nextcloud_Logo.svg_.png?fit=760%2C539&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="" />
&lt;/a>&lt;a href="https://nextcloud.com/install/#" title="https://nextcloud.com/install/#">Get started with Nextcloud&lt;/a>
There are a lot of benefits to running your own private ‘cloud’ storage system, but for me, my top concern is privacy and Nextcloud gives me the ability to take accountability for my own data. With this in mind, I am conscious of my Nextcloud server going offline or suffering data loss, so I want a way to create 1 or more backups of my datacentre hosted, Nextcloud data on my home NAS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Convert an ESXi VM to UNRAID KVM with qume-img convert</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/convert-an-esxi-vm-to-unraid-kvm-with-qume-img-convert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 20:11:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/convert-an-esxi-vm-to-unraid-kvm-with-qume-img-convert/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vmdk_to_kvm.jpg?resize=133%2C133&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Convert ESXi VM to UNRAID KVM" />
Here’s a quick guide on how to convert ESXi VMs to and UNRAID KVM virtual machine – it’s a simple process but a minefield to navigate on searches and forums.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I currently have a windows 10 VM running on an ESXi server (vmdk) which I want to migrate to my UNRAID server which uses KVM to host VMs. The vmdk file is unfortunately thick provisioned, so I have had to do some disk juggling, due to my limited amount of available of space on my array.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Backup Google Photos with Rclone</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 23:47:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google photos auto backup is a nice way to make sure that all your photos on your mobile phone are backed up. It takes the pain out of backups by allowing you to automatically upload your photos and videos to Google servers. For those who would also like an offline copy of those photos, it is now easy to automate this. Here is how to backup your Google Photos library to your local computer or NAS with Rclone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kali Linux 2020.1 - No more root by default</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kali-linux-2020-1-no-more-root-by-default/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 22:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kali-linux-2020-1-no-more-root-by-default/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kali.org/" title="https://www.kali.org/">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kali-2020.1-logo.png?resize=116%2C68&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Kali Linux 2020.1" />
&lt;/a>
Rejoice! Kali Linux 2020.1 is here! The first release of 2020 has arrived and this post will contain some updates and my initial thoughts on the fresh release.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kali-linux-20201-features-and-changes">Kali Linux 2020.1 features and changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.kali.org/news/kali-default-non-root-user/" title="https://www.kali.org/news/kali-default-non-root-user/">Non-Root by default&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Kali single installer image&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.kali.org/docs/nethunter/nethunter-rootless/" title="https://www.kali.org/docs/nethunter/nethunter-rootless/">Kali NetHunter Rootless&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improvements to theme &amp;amp; kali-undercover&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Full Kali release notes as per their release blog post: &lt;a href="https://www.kali.org/releases/kali-linux-2020-1-release/" title="https://www.kali.org/releases/kali-linux-2020-1-release/">https://www.kali.org/releases/kali-linux-2020-1-release/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Secure DDNS - Namecheap SSL With DDClient</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/secure-ddns-namecheap-ssl-with-ddclient/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 21:12:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/secure-ddns-namecheap-ssl-with-ddclient/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/ddclient-logo.png?resize=121%2C120&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="namecheap ssl ddclient" />
&lt;a href="https://ddclient.net/" title="https://ddclient.net/">https://ddclient.net&lt;/a>
A quote short post on how to secure your DDNS updates with Namecheap, SSL and DDClient. For those of us who use dynamic DNS to work around roaming IP addresses, it is important to make sure that you are updating your DNS records securely with SSL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default DDclient config has an example configuration file for using Namecheap’s DDNS service, however, it does not use SSL to check for your IP. In theory that connection could be manipulated and a false IP result could be returned – updating your DNS records to a wrong, malicious IP could cause a number of problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to make a VirtualBox VM the same resolution as host</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-make-a-virtualbox-vm-the-same-resolution-as-host/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 09:05:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-make-a-virtualbox-vm-the-same-resolution-as-host/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yet another simple problem/resolution. If you are looking to make your &lt;a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/" title="https://www.virtualbox.org/">VirtualBox&lt;/a> VM’s resolution match that of your host making full-screen mode, truly full screen, look no further, here is the answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again we are looking at an issue caused by a default setting. You can set your VM to full-screen mode, but it not likely to rescale to the native resolution of your display.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The setting which you need to change requires you to have the VM powered off. Enter the settings for the VM &amp;gt; Display &amp;gt; Screen Tab &amp;gt; Graphics Controller: &lt;strong>VBoxSVGA&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to enable subnet overlapping on a Fortigate</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-enable-subnet-overlapping-on-a-fortigate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 12:40:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-enable-subnet-overlapping-on-a-fortigate/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fortigate-subnet-overlapping.jpg?resize=155%2C155&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="fortgiate subnet overlapping" />
A short and sweet problem/resolution. If you are looking to enable subnet overlapping on a Fortigate so that you can give multiple interfaces an IP in the same subnet, this is the post for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NOTE: This feature can only be enabled in the Fortigate’s CLI. To enable the overlapping feature, enter the following commands:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>config system settings
set allow-subnet-overlap [enable/disable]
end
&lt;/code>&lt;/pr</description></item><item><title>Python 2.7 end-of-life - The time to upgrade is upon us</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-2-7-end-of-life-the-time-to-upgrade-is-upon-us/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 02:31:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/python-2-7-end-of-life-the-time-to-upgrade-is-upon-us/</guid><description>&lt;p>1st January 2020 marked the official end of python 2.7 development, including feature support and security fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Python-PNG-Clipart.png?resize=231%2C144" alt="Python 2.7 end-of-life" />
Python 2.7 was over 9 years old in development years, making it the longest supported version to date. The code freeze is no in place, with the final release – 2.7.18 – scheduled for an April 2020 release. So yes there will be one more version to come down the tubes but it’s probably best that the new python project you were thinking of starting is written in 3.7 or above.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kasa home automation with IFTTT and python webhooks</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kasa-home-automation-with-ifttt-and-python-webhooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kasa-home-automation-with-ifttt-and-python-webhooks/</guid><description>&lt;p>They say that the long tail page titles are best for SEO, well this one certainly should be up there with the best of them. In this post, I am going to explain how easy it is to control Kasa a HS100 / HS110 with IFTTT and python webhooks. Using this basic code, you expand into building a very powerful home automation system which fits your needs and take your Kasa home automation to the next level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWUS036AC (rtl8812au) driver setup in Kali Linux</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/awus036ac-rt8812au-driver-setup-in-kali-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 12:34:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/awus036ac-rt8812au-driver-setup-in-kali-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am planning a number of articles which focus on using aircrack-ng and hashcast to recover WPA wireless security passwords. However to get into that you need to have a specific wireless device which supports monitor mode and packet injection. I decided on the Alfa AWUS036AC, but some work was required to get the drivers installed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wireless-signal-1119306_640.png?resize=182%2C124&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="AWUS036AC Driver Installation" />
This guide is based on Kali Linux 2019.4 – but the drivers are certified for earlier versions of Kali and the kernel that 2019.4 uses. See updates below for getting this working on Kali 2020.4.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kali Linux - How to upgrade python 2.7 to python 3.7</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kali-linux-how-to-upgrade-python-2-7-to-python-3-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/kali-linux-how-to-upgrade-python-2-7-to-python-3-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have covered changing the default version of python in Debian, however for those looking to Google for a quick fix on Kali, I hope that this reaches you well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was tested on a completely fresh install of Kali Linux with no other alterations made prior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The basic premise is to configure Kali to use python 3.7 at a higher priority to python 2.7 or any other version installed on the system.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ubuntu 19.10 - How to upgrade python 2.7 to python 3.7</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/ubuntu-19-10-how-to-upgrade-python-2-7-to-python-3-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/ubuntu-19-10-how-to-upgrade-python-2-7-to-python-3-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Much to my surprise, I found that a fresh install of Ubuntu 19.10 was set to use python 2.7 as the default python instance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have covered changing the default version of python in Debian, however for those looking to Google for a quick fix on Ubuntu 19.10, I hope that this reaches you well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was tested on a completely fresh install of Ubuntu 19.10 with no other alterations made prior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with Python 3 - a beginner's cheat sheet</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/getting-started-with-python-3-a-beginners-cheat-sheet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 21:13:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/getting-started-with-python-3-a-beginners-cheat-sheet/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.python.org/" title="https://www.python.org/">&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i1.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Python-PNG-Clipart.png?resize=187%2C117" alt="Python Logo" />
&lt;/a>Python.Org
I have been getting started with python 3 – I want to make this my primary scripting language. One way I like to assist myself whilst I learn the rope is to maintain a crib sheet filled with all the trivial things I would otherwise forget.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="python-3-cheat-sheet">Python 3 Cheat Sheet&lt;/h2>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>
#Define Variables
programming_languages: &amp;#34;Python&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;VB&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;C++&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;C#&amp;#34;
#Print Variables
print(programming_languages)
print(&amp;#39;--------------------&amp;#39;)
#Basic for loop + variables
for language in programming_languages:
print(language)
print(&amp;#39;--------------------&amp;#39;)
#Basic Function
def FuncExample():
i: 1
for language in programming_languages:
#Concatinate Strings and Integers in print statements
print(&amp;#34;Language &amp;#34; + str(i) + &amp;#34;:&amp;#34; + language)
#Increment Integer
i += 1
FuncExample()
print(&amp;#39;--------------------&amp;#39;)
#Functions with Variables #1 - Strings
def FuncVarExample1(fname, lname):
#Print with CRLF
print(&amp;#34;First Name: &amp;#34; + fname + &amp;#34;\r\n&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;Last Name: &amp;#34; + lname)
FuncVarExample1(&amp;#34;Joe&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Bloggs&amp;#34;)
print(&amp;#39;--------------------&amp;#39;)
#Functions with Variables #2 - Integers + Returning Values
def FuncVarExample2(x, y):
#Basic integer maths
return x+y
#Concatenating Strings and Integers
print(&amp;#34;33 + 42: &amp;#34; + str(FuncVarExample2(33,42)))
print(&amp;#39;--------------------&amp;#39;)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pr</description></item><item><title>Clipboard and Shared Folders on Kali Linux with VirtualBox</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/clipboard-and-shared-folders-on-kali-linux-with-virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 21:21:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/clipboard-and-shared-folders-on-kali-linux-with-virtualbox/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent more time that care to admit trying to setup a shared folder between my windows host and Kali VirtualBox VM. So hopefully the Google algos pick this one up and save you the time trying to find the right packages to fix this a clipboard sync.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>apt-get update
apt-get install -y virtualbox-guest-x11
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Go for a quick reboot once the above commands are complete and you should have clipboard sync (text) and shared folders should mount successfully.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[SOLVED] - Running Docker on a Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/solved-running-docker-on-a-raspberry-pi-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 08:26:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/solved-running-docker-on-a-raspberry-pi-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Raspberry Pi 4 has now been released offering up to 4GB of RAM! All of the horsepower required for an excellent lower power, docker host.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i2.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Pi4-Docker.png?resize=774%2C492" alt="Pi4 Running Docker" />
However, there are currently issues undergoing work which prevent docker from running on the only Rasbian image currently available for the Pi 4 – ‘&lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/raspbian/" title="https://www.raspberrypi.org/downloads/raspbian/">Rasbian Buster&lt;/a>‘. Details of these issues can been found here on the GitHub thread – &lt;a href="https://github.com/docker/for-linux/issues/709" title="https://github.com/docker/for-linux/issues/709">https://github.com/docker/for-linux/issues/709&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Changing the default python version in Debian</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/changing-the-default-python-version-in-debian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 20:48:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/changing-the-default-python-version-in-debian/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a previous &lt;a href="https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/" title="https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/">post&lt;/a>, I explained how to upgrade from Python3.5 to Python3.7, however is is still the case in most fresh Debian installs that the default python version is 2.7. This post is going to show you the simple steps you need to take when changing the default python version in Debian.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide is based on a Debian 9 installation, but work for multiple releases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using a DHT11 sensor with a raspberry pi</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/using-a-dht11-sensor-with-a-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/using-a-dht11-sensor-with-a-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is going to share how to use DHT11 sensors with a the raspberry pi , using the GPIO pins. Furthermore the particular sensor that I am going to be discussing requires zero soldering and is purely plug and play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The Sensor:&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
The sensor that we will be using is the DHT11 – the exact variant is the 3 pin version. You can find the exact version that I used here&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Double NAT port forwarding with a Fortigate</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/double-nat-port-forwarding-with-a-fortigate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 13:10:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/double-nat-port-forwarding-with-a-fortigate/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are unfortunate enough to have to deal with double NAT on your gateway then you might know the troubles surrounding portforwarding or VIPs. Here is a quick how to guide for setting up a port forward on a Forgate where double NAT is inplace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Case Study – Plex port forward&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plex is a great tool for managing your personal media collection and it gets even better when you enable a port forward to let you access this collection from anywhere in the world. Whilst Plex ahve made a number of changes to allow you to reach your contect via a relay server, the best way to access your content from outside your LAN is by using a port forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debian 9 - Running a python script at boot</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-running-a-python-script-at-startup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 18:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-running-a-python-script-at-startup/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are a number of ways that you can run a python or bash script at system start but I am about to show you possibly the easiest way, using crontab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First you need to make that your script is executable and can run unattended. Then you need to login as the user your wish to execute the script as and edit the crontab file:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>crontab -e
&lt;/code>&lt;/pr</description></item><item><title>Debian 9 - How to upgrade python 3.5 to python 3.7</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 18:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Python-Upgrade.png?resize=208%2C208&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Python upgrade 3.5 to 3.7" />
I recently spent 30 minutes figuring out how to upgrade to python 3.7 and subsequently pip version on a fresh install of Debian 9. I ran into a number of issues doing this so I though that I would put this quick post together to make this a little bit less complicated for anyone else trying to this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post relates specifically to python version 3.7.3. Although the generic commands should also apply to earlier versions, but your milage may vary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating a local DNS server with Pi Hole</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/creating-a-local-dns-server-with-pi-hole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 09:00:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/creating-a-local-dns-server-with-pi-hole/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a local DNS server for local DNS requests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is going to explain the why and how I created a local DNS server in my home network environment. I used the PiHole project to make a network wide advert blocking a reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/" title="https://pi-hole.net/">https://pi-hole.net/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have previously created a DNS server using Bind, running on CentOS 7. Thankfully digital ocean came to my rescue with some of the config in this home lab project, so be sure to check out their guide if you are looking for slightly higher level DNS setup:&lt;br>
&lt;a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-configure-bind-as-a-private-network-dns-server-on-centos-7" title="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-configure-bind-as-a-private-network-dns-server-on-centos-7">https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-configure-bind-as-a-private-network-dns-server-on-centos-7&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modifying Windows shortcuts is Powershell</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/modifying-windows-shortcuts-is-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 09:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/modifying-windows-shortcuts-is-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://i0.wp.com/exitcode0.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/PowerShell_5.0_icon-150x150.png?resize=150%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="PowerShell_5.0_icon" />
I once faced a rather tedious task that involved recursively modifying a number of shortcut paths stored across a convoluted folder structure. There was approximately 100 shortcuts which needed part of their path modifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The answer: &lt;strong>Create a****PowerShell script.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following code utilises regex to check for the existence of a string and modify with the define replacement. It is easily possible to use Read-Host to make this a little bit more interactive, but the purposes of my use-case it was just as simple to modify these variables before running the script.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Powershell - Checking the Language Mode</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/powershell-checking-the-language-mode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 09:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/powershell-checking-the-language-mode/</guid><description>&lt;p>For security purposes, it is possible to control the language mode in a given Powershell session. These language modes can constrict which modules can be loaded during the life of a powershell session.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learn mode about Powershell langeuage modes: &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/module/microsoft.powershell.core/about/about_language_modes?view=powershell-6" title="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/module/microsoft.powershell.core/about/about_language_modes?view=powershell-6">About Language Modes – Microsoft&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="detect-the-current-language-mode">Detect the Current Language Mode&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>$sLangMode: $ExecutionContext.SessionState.LanguageMode&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If ($sLangMode -ne “FullLanguage”){&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Write-Host ” !! Unable to run scrit – Powershell Using Wrong Language Mode !! ”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>'Copy, Paste' With Powershell Sendkeys</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-with-powershell-sendkeys/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 22:17:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/copy-paste-with-powershell-sendkeys/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is really quick nugget of Powershell for anyone who is struggling to copy and paste into a particular window or dialog box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps it is a case of a website which prevents text form being sent to a field from the clipboard, or in my case, a windows UAC prompt. If you are following password best practices, your passwords should be long, complex and contain zero dictionary words. Furthermore, you should have a different password for every site and service. &lt;strong>So&lt;/strong>, when a user interface doesn’t allow you to paste a password, life gets that little bit more difficult.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>We collect usage data using google analytics for the purposes of visualizing the traffic on this website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All data is anonymized and we do not sell or share any data with third parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you choose to deny, no info will be collected whatsoever.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>