<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Bash on ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/categories/bash/</link><description>Recent content in Bash on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/categories/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating Postgres Deployment with Docker Compose and Init Scripts</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automating-postgres-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/automating-postgres-deployment/</guid><description>Introduction to Running PostgreSQL in a Docker Container using Docker Compose In this blog post, we will explore how to run PostgreSQL in a Docker container using Docker Compose. We will also break down and explain the init-user-db.sh script that is executed at startup to initialize the PostgreSQL tables. Running PostgreSQL in a Docker container provides several benefits, including ease of deployment, portability, and isolation. So let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and understand the process!</description></item><item><title>How To call a bash command with variables in Python</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-call-a-bash-command-with-variables-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-call-a-bash-command-with-variables-in-python/</guid><description>A quick Google of the above only seemed to give me answers for the inverse, calling a python script from a bash shell and handing it variables. At least, the first 3 results showed this and I’m probably not alone when it comes to scrolling down past the StackOverflow articles.
So I am had to go it alone and the way that I figured out how to call a bash command with variables in Python (3), is a total hack… But it works.</description></item></channel></rss>