<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>debian on ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/categories/debian/</link><description>Recent content in debian on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/categories/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debian 10 - How to upgrade python 3.7 to python 3.9</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-10-how-to-upgrade-python-3-7-to-python-3-9/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-10-how-to-upgrade-python-3-7-to-python-3-9/</guid><description>I have covered this a number of times in the past and the posts have proved popular and useful to many. So, here is my guide for updating to the latest version of Python 3 (3.9) on Debian 10 Buster.
To clarify the purpose of this guide, Debian 10 ships with Python 2 (2.7) and Python 3 (3.7) installed at my time of writing. For those wishing to upgrade from python 3.</description></item><item><title>Debian 9 - Running a python script at boot</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-running-a-python-script-at-startup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 18:30:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-running-a-python-script-at-startup/</guid><description>There are a number of ways that you can run a python or bash script at system start but I am about to show you possibly the easiest way, using crontab.
First you need to make that your script is executable and can run unattended. Then you need to login as the user your wish to execute the script as and edit the crontab file:
crontab -e If this is your first time editing the crontab file, you might be asked which editor you wish to use – I chose nano.</description></item><item><title>Debian 9 - How to upgrade python 3.5 to python 3.7</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 18:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/debian-9-how-to-upgrade-python-3-5-to-python-3-7/</guid><description>I recently spent 30 minutes figuring out how to upgrade to python 3.7 and subsequently pip version on a fresh install of Debian 9. I ran into a number of issues doing this so I though that I would put this quick post together to make this a little bit less complicated for anyone else trying to this.
This post relates specifically to python version 3.7.3. Although the generic commands should also apply to earlier versions, but your milage may vary.</description></item></channel></rss>