<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>backups on ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/categories/backups/</link><description>Recent content in backups on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 21:08:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/categories/backups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backup Nextcloud with RCLONE</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 21:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-nextcloud-with-rclone/</guid><description>I’ve made previous posts about backing cloud services with RCLONE – Backup Google Photos with Rclone – and this post will detail how to backup a self-hosted cloud service, Nextcloud.
Get started with Nextcloud There are a lot of benefits to running your own private ‘cloud’ storage system, but for me, my top concern is privacy and Nextcloud gives me the ability to take accountability for my own data. With this in mind, I am conscious of my Nextcloud server going offline or suffering data loss, so I want a way to create 1 or more backups of my datacentre hosted, Nextcloud data on my home NAS.</description></item><item><title>Backup Google Photos with Rclone</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 23:47:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/backup-google-photos-with-rclone/</guid><description>Google photos auto backup is a nice way to make sure that all your photos on your mobile phone are backed up. It takes the pain out of backups by allowing you to automatically upload your photos and videos to Google servers. For those who would also like an offline copy of those photos, it is now easy to automate this. Here is how to backup your Google Photos library to your local computer or NAS with Rclone.</description></item></channel></rss>