<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Raspberry Pi on ExitCode0</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/categories/raspberry-pi/</link><description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on ExitCode0</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 10:31:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://exitcode0.net/categories/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How To: Raspberry Pi boot from USB</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-raspberry-pi-boot-from-usb/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 10:31:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/how-to-raspberry-pi-boot-from-usb/</guid><description>The Pi enthusiasts have been waiting for official USB boot support on the Raspberry Pi for what feels like a lifetime, but finally it is on the horizon. In this post I will explain how to make your Raspberry Pi boot from USB.
WARNING: Although this is official, it is still in beta testing, so rock-solid stability is far from certain. Learn more about this beta release here.
Why should I make my Raspberry Pi boot from USB?</description></item><item><title>[SOLVED] - Running Docker on a Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/solved-running-docker-on-a-raspberry-pi-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 08:26:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/solved-running-docker-on-a-raspberry-pi-4/</guid><description>The Raspberry Pi 4 has now been released offering up to 4GB of RAM! All of the horsepower required for an excellent lower power, docker host.
However, there are currently issues undergoing work which prevent docker from running on the only Rasbian image currently available for the Pi 4 – ‘Rasbian Buster‘. Details of these issues can been found here on the GitHub thread – https://github.com/docker/for-linux/issues/709
Current Working Solution Fear not, for there is a simple way to fool your docker installation and successfully getting it to run on the Pi 4.</description></item><item><title>Using a DHT11 sensor with a raspberry pi</title><link>https://exitcode0.net/posts/using-a-dht11-sensor-with-a-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://exitcode0.net/posts/using-a-dht11-sensor-with-a-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>This post is going to share how to use DHT11 sensors with a the raspberry pi , using the GPIO pins. Furthermore the particular sensor that I am going to be discussing requires zero soldering and is purely plug and play.
The Sensor:
The sensor that we will be using is the DHT11 – the exact variant is the 3 pin version. You can find the exact version that I used here</description></item></channel></rss>